Okay, so in this video
then, we are going to
discuss some procurement
strategies and phases.
So, strategies and phases as it relates to
procurement.
Now, whereas the procurement management
plan is documenting how we're going to
plan, execute, monitoring, control,
or procurement management process,
once we have decided that we are going to
outsource the work, once it's been
determined, so remember in planning,
or rather remember in the procurement
management plan, we're
documenting all the procedures to
determine are we're going to
outsource the worker do it in-house.
Once we've decided, yes, we're going to
outsource the work.
Once it's been determined that we need to
use a vendor, then we now need to develop
some kind of strategy, some kind of
strategy in, you know, how we're going to
negotiate, what are we going to negotiate,
what kind of contracts are we going to
negotiate, who's going to be negotiating
and so and so forth.
We're going to come up with some kind of
strategy.
to actually, you know,
outsource the work and reach out
to vendors, deal with our
vendors, and so and so forth.
So three common strategy approaches,
right, and the three that I mentioned
essentially in PIMBOC are these three,
delivery method, contract payment types,
procurement phases.
What kind of phases are we going to have?
You're going to have different phases
based on the type of project, right?
So phases, in this case, we're talking
about procurement, procurement phases.
Again, more about that in just a second,
right, but contract.
payment types, what kind of contracts are
we going to have?
Who's going to be negotiating the type of
contracts?
What type of contracts do we prefer?
And then when it comes
to payment, how often are
we going to pay our
vendors and so and so forth?
Also things like the, here, delivery
method.
First and foremost, delivery method.
So how, well, first of all, the how is
documented in the management plan,
the procurement management plan.
But here now we're coming up with the
actual strategy.
Right.
So as a very simple example, is
subcontracting allowed?
Will subcontracting be allowed in this
case?
Right.
So we are going to hire a vendor,
and now this vendor may be hiring their
own subcontractor to perform some of the
work.
Is that okay for us?
It may be, it might not be.
Right, so as a very simple
example, let's say I've hired
someone, we've hired
someone to develop our website.
So we've hired this company to develop our
website.
Now, this vendor, they
may outsource some of
their work, some of the
development work offshore.
So they've got their own subcontractors
that they use right in a foreign country.
Are we going to allow that?
Do we want that?
For us, if we are developing a website,
that might make no difference to us,
right?
Whether it's done here, whether it's done
somewhere else, right?
I mean, basically, if their
subcontractor messes up,
then we are going to be
holding our contractor, right?
Our primary vendor liable.
Whether they outsource it to their own
subcontractor, whether they use our
internal users, we don't really care about
that.
However, what if there was some
confidential information involved?
If it's a large project, there's a lot of
confidentiality going around.
Well, we want to know who has access to
all that information.
So in that case, we might not allow
subcontractors.
Or if they are going to utilize their own
subcontractors, then we
need to know who they are.
We actually need to hire them because now
we want to have a contract with their
subcontractor if they have access to some
of our confidential information.
So again, what's our strategy?
Are we going to allow that?
So that's what we mean by procurement
strategy.
I mean, basically things like that,
we need to understand that up front.
Also, things like, for example,
are we truly hiring somebody?
Are we going to hire an actual vendor?
Or is this going to be some kind of temporary
partnership, right, a joint venture?
Also, things like, you know, is this
procurement, is it a custom design?
Is it like a cookie cutter, a standard
design?
Again, these are just
basic little strategies
that we want to, what
we want to understand.
Also, things like, as I mentioned,
payment type, contract payment types.
So first of all, in a separate video,
we're going to cover the different types
of contracts, but what kind of contract
would we like to negotiate?
So in a separate video, we are going to
cover different types of contracts.
So what kind of contract is going to work
for us?
That's the kind of contract we want to
push the vendor.
towards.
Also, when it comes to payment, how often
are we going to be paying the vendor?
Do we want to pay them the one time right
at the end?
Or are we going to have various,
we're going to pay them at various stages?
And then procurement phases.
So what are all the different phases
involved in the procurement?
As a very simple example on this next
slide.
These are some common phases that you
might find on a IT-type project,
but it's going to vary.
It's going vary by industry and project
and so and so forth.
But we need to have some kind of phases
here.
Again, remember, we are the customer.
We're the customer.
We are outsourcing the work to a vendor.
So even then, I mean, the vendor may have
some of their own development phases,
but in our case, we're talking about
phases regarding the procurement,
regarding the procurement with a vendor.
So these are just some of the common
phases that you might see on an IT type
project, planning and analysis, we are
giving our requirements to the customer.
So when and how, what kind of requirements
are we going to give them?
How are we going to come up with the scope
of this procurement in this case?
So that's one phase, planning an analysis
phase.
Then we're going to come up with the
detailed design phase.
Who is going to come up with a design?
Are we coming up with a design and then
giving it to the very very?
vendor or is the vendor
themselves going to come up
with a design and then
giving it to us for our sign-off.
Once we've gone through the detailed
design, then the implementation,
right, the installation.
So the implementation is the work that's
going to be done by the vendor.
So they have their own phase.
For us, it's implementation of the actual
work, right?
So now they're going to be implementing
the work, then what?
We need to test it.
So we have a testing.
We might have a testing phase.
So we inspect the work, we're testing the
work that the vendor is doing,
signing off on the work so that now they
can start, you know, delivering it to us.
But as they're delivering it, handover and
transition, we're about testing.
Or rather, what about the training?
Who's going to be training?
How are we going to be trained on this new
product?
Do we need any training?
If so, is a vendor going to provide us
with the training, right?
Or do we do we have to go to a different
vendor, right, to be trained?
Let's again, that needs to be understood.
So these are all the do, again,
another phase, right?
And then hand over and transition,
right?
So they are now physically handing over
this product or this IT network to us,
transitioning it over onto our service.
And then, of course, support and
maintenance.
So this will be then after the project,
after the project is done, right?
then, you know, what's the support of
maintenance requirements and so and so forth.
So these are just some common phases,
you know, in a typical IT type project.
But of course, like I said, it's going to
be different for every project,
right, different based on
the size and nature of the
project as well as the
industry and so and so forth.
But again, all of these need to be
understood.
Right.
So in plan procurement management,
or rather as far as the procurement
management plan is concerned, we're
documenting how we're going to plan,
execute, monitoring control our
procurement process.
Once we've determined
that we are going to outsource
the work, then what
is a strategy involved?
So we've got the strategy and then within
the strategy then what are all the common
phases that we need to go through,
you know, for a successful procurement.